<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rubrics on ESPM 157</title>
    <link>/rubrics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rubrics on ESPM 157</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/rubrics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Module Rubric</title>
      <link>/rubrics/climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rubrics/climate/</guid>
      <description>3 pts for use of git hub
 0pts: no repo or a repo with no unique commits 1pts: evidence of at least one commit. read me not updated 2pts: evidence of semiregular commits, read me updated only partially - either missing name of team member or failing to update the read me from the template 3pts: evidence of multiple commits, read me updated to reflect the repos purpose, team member name and handle included   3 pts for Rmarkdown</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fish Module Rubric</title>
      <link>/rubrics/fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rubrics/fish/</guid>
      <description>2 pt for use of GitHub  are both users pushing/pulling? have they successfully dealt with merge conflicts (if any)? have they updated their repository README with names and module details?  2 pts for travis  is their build passing? is the travis badge included and displaying correctly on their .md documents  2 pts for Rmarkdown  do they include a .md file along with their .Rmd assignment file?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Module Rubric</title>
      <link>/rubrics/spatial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rubrics/spatial/</guid>
      <description>2 pt for use of git hub  are both users pushing/pulling? have they successfully dealt with merge conflicts? have they updated their repository README with names and module details?  2 pts for travis  is their build passing? is the travis badge included and displaying correctly on their .md documents  2 pts for Rmarkdown  do they include a .md file along with their .Rmd assignment file?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>