<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Assignments on ESPM 157</title>
    <link>/assignment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Assignments on ESPM 157</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/assignment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/assignment/fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignment/fish/</guid>
      <description>Unit 3: Fisheries Collapse Module This module will focus on understanding and replicating fisheries stock assessment data and fisheries collapse. Follow along with Carl, as he live codes the first exercise and then complete the second as your group assignment.
The Database We will use data from the RAM Legacy Stock Assessment Database
First, load in the necessary librarys. Note that this time we need a package we haven’t used before readxl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Exercise</title>
      <link>/assignment/climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignment/climate/</guid>
      <description>Attention: To get started on the exercise, visit the Piazza post to create your team repo.
Unit I: Climate Change Module Warm-up exercise: Examining CO2 trends in R  Example from http://climate.nasa.gov/vital-signs/carbon-dioxide/ Raw data from ftp://aftp.cmdl.noaa.gov/products/trends/co2/co2_mm_mlo.txt  Which months are the CO2 values at the maximum? Minimum? Why is this?
What rolling average is used in computing the “trend” line? How does the trend depend on the rolling average?
  Exercise I: Temperature Data Each of the last years has consecutively set new records on global climate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extinctions Unit</title>
      <link>/assignment/extinction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignment/extinction/</guid>
      <description>Extinctions Module Are we experiencing the sixth great extinction?
What is the current pace of extinction? Is it accelerating? How does it compare to background extinction rates?
 Background  Section Intro Video Ceballos et al (2015)   Computational Topics  Accessing data from a RESTful API Error handling JSON data format Regular expressions Working with missing values   Additional references:  http://www.hhmi.org/biointeractive/biodiversity-age-humans (Video) Barnosky et al. (2011) Pimm et al (2014) Sandom et al (2014)   Getting started (based on live code session) CURL and REST Use the httr package to make a single API query against the following endpoint: http://api.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project: Proposal</title>
      <link>/assignment/proposal-final/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignment/proposal-final/</guid>
      <description>Please prepare a short proposal on your final project idea for next Thursday, Nov 2. The proposal should include:
 Title &amp;amp; description of the project Your name &amp;amp; partner&amp;rsquo;s name A description of the data required, and how it will be obtained (e.g. URL/DOI to data source) 3 questions / analysis tasks you will perform on the data; in the spirit of the assignments we have been doing.  You may choose to work with your partner or independently on the final project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population dynamics assignment</title>
      <link>/assignment/popdyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignment/popdyn/</guid>
      <description>Attention: To get started on the exercise, visit the Piazza post to create your team repo.
In this section, we will explore population dynamics of multiple interacting species; or more generally, dynamics in multiple variables. Previously, our only dynamic variable was a single focal population, sometimes called x, or squirrels, that could change over time in response to how many other squirrels there were. All other aspects of system were fixed: such as the environmental conditions responsible for determining the growth rate r and carrying capacity K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Assignment</title>
      <link>/assignment/spatial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignment/spatial/</guid>
      <description>Exercise This module is inspired by a recent paper in Nature Ecology and Evolution, Mapping the global potential for marine aquaculture. The authors used multiple constraints including ship traffic, dissolved oxygen, bottom depth and more, to limit and map areas suitable for aquaculture.
 We are going to use a similar, but much more simplified approach here. We will map potential areas of marine aquaculture for the super cute Pacific spiny lumpsucker (Eumicrotremus orbis)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fish reproducibility</title>
      <link>/assignment/2017-10-24-fish-reproducibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignment/2017-10-24-fish-reproducibility/</guid>
      <description>Set visibility settings on your repository Review the repo of another team, making direct edits for improvements:  Overall presentation:  travis passing, badged? information in readme, yaml header output files committed   Rmd inspection  Remove extraneous / duplicate code blocks. Request narrative text where text is missing executable, top-to-bottom?   Understand and compare results:  Data table strategies: joining vs separate tables Can the code be made more consise?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>