<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ESPM 157: Data Science for Global Change Ecology on ESPM 157</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ESPM 157: Data Science for Global Change Ecology on ESPM 157</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>warning  clear  Please note: Syllabus under development, subject to change    
 Date Module Data Topics Read Watch   2018-01-18 home  Introduction &amp; setup         CLIMATE MODULE     2018-01-23   Individual assessment     2018-01-25   Workflow: GitHub, RMarkdown, Travis     2018-01-30   Visualization basics     2018-02-01   Manipulation basics         OVERFISHING MODULE     2018-02-06 directions_boat  Relational data: groups     2018-02-08  directions_boat  Relational data: joins     2018-02-13  directions_boat  group_by and summarize     2018-02-15  directions_boat  Missing Values     2018-02-20  directions_boat  Reproducibility     2018-02-22 language  web design         POPULATION DYNAMICS MODULE     2018-02-27 bug_report memory Functions     2018-03-01  bug_report memory Iteration     2018-03-06  bug_report memory Iteration     2018-03-08     Writing R packages         GEOSPATIAL CHANGE MODULE     2018-03-13 my_location satellite geospatial intro, visualization     2018-03-15 my_location satellite vector data     2018-03-20 my_location satellite raster data     2018-03-22  cloud  Tutorial: Docker &amp; Cloud computing     2018-04-03 school  Final Project Proposals         MASS EXTINCTIONS MODULE     2018-04-05 trending_down widgets REST APIs     2018-04-10  trending_down widgets Regular Expressions     2018-04-12 trending_down widgets Data rectangling     2018-04-17 trending_down widgets Data rectangling         BIODIVERSITY MODULE / FINAL PROJECTS     2018-04-19 nature_people share JSON-LD, graph queries     2018-04-24 school  Final Projects     2018-04-26 nature_people share Data publishing     2018-05-01 school  Final Projects     2018-05-03 school  Final Projects       </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policies</title>
      <link>/policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/policies/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites You should be generally numerically literate, and some prior programming experience will be helpful. Students new to programming might find Hands on Programming with R to be helpful. Students with significant experience in programming and statistical analysis should find themselves well prepared but should find plenty still to learn in each lesson.
Instructional Methods As a flipped classroom, students are provided with either reading or video material that they are expected to view/read prior to class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description> ESPM 157 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/overview-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview-notes/</guid>
      <description>tutorial for Data Science Triad: GitHub, RMarkdown, Travis-CI
rstudio Watch: - RStudio IDE, Part I
Read: readings/setup.md - Prerequisites - Running R code - RStudio Cheat sheet (for reference)
rmarkdown Watch:
 Reports with RMarkdown (by Garrett Grolemund)  Read:
 Introduction [r4ds-27.1] R Markdown [r4ds-27.2] Code chunks [r4ds-27.4]  git Watch:
DataCamp Lesson: RStudio IDE, Part II, Chapter 2: Version Control (by Garrett Grolemund).
vis.1 Watch:
 Tidyverse Chapter 2: Data Visualization (David Robinson)  (Yes, we&amp;rsquo;re starting with Chapter 2, we&amp;rsquo;ll go back to Chapter 1 soon).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Background on Fish Collapse Data</title>
      <link>/read/fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/fish/</guid>
      <description>The material for this session is a little different, aiming at background on the scientific issues rather than background on the method. Do take a moment to look over the papers and short documentary. Do also review the previous references to make sure you are comfortable with group_by() and summarize() patterns.
Watch  Background abbreviated documentary, features many of the leading authors on both sides https://vimeo.com/44104959  Read  Original 2006 paper: Worm, B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Exercise</title>
      <link>/assignments/climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignments/climate/</guid>
      <description>Unit I: Climate Change Module Warm-up exercise: Examining CO2 trends in R  Example from http://climate.nasa.gov/vital-signs/carbon-dioxide/ Raw data from ftp://aftp.cmdl.noaa.gov/products/trends/co2/co2_mm_mlo.txt  Which months are the CO2 values at the maximum? Minimum? Why is this?
What rolling average is used in computing the “trend” line? How does the trend depend on the rolling average?
  Exercise I: Temperature Data Last year, 2015, has now been confirmed as the warmest year on record.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Manipulation Basics</title>
      <link>/read/dplyr-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/dplyr-1/</guid>
      <description> Watch  Tidyverse Chapter 1: Data Wrangling (David Robinson)  Read  dplyr basic verbs: filter, arrange, select, and mutate, [r4ds-5.1 - 5.5]  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project: Proposal</title>
      <link>/assignments/final/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignments/final/</guid>
      <description>Projects should essentially look like any of our modules, but with you identifying the dataset and questions rather than working from a template. You may choose to replicate a figure from an existing study, but are also encouraged to use this opportunity to perform some exploratory analysis on data you may be using in your DS421 team projects or your own dissertation research. Remember that as with modules, finals will be graded on workflow and presentation rather than particular conclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functions</title>
      <link>/read/functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/functions/</guid>
      <description> Watch  DataCamp Lesson: Writing Functions in R, Chapter 1-2 (Hadley Wickham)  Chapters 3-5 introduce the purrr package for functional programming, which we&amp;rsquo;ll see more later in the unit.
Read  R for Data Science textbook: [r4ds-19]  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Data &amp; Visualization</title>
      <link>/read/geospatial-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/geospatial-1/</guid>
      <description>Reading Our geospatial module is meant only as an introduction to geospatial data, an already-rich area in R that is in mid-Renaissance right now, just as tabular data was in the past few years since the introduction of dplyr and the rest of tidyverse.
GeoSpatial Textbook: Geocomputation with R (Lovelace, Nowosad, Muenchow)
 Chapter 1: Introduction  Basic Visualization tools Also read over the following vignettes:
 Static maps: tmap Vignette Interactive maps: mapview Vignette  Watch UPDATED  DataCamp now has a more modern course from Zev Ross, Spatial Analysis in R with sf and raster that more closely aligns with the tools we will be using in this module (matching the Geocomputation reading above).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Data Input/Output</title>
      <link>/read/geospatial-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/geospatial-io/</guid>
      <description> Watch Spatial Analysis in R with sf and raster Chapter 1.
Reading Geospatial Textbook: Geocomputation with R (Lovelace, Nowosad, Muenchow)
 Chapter 6: Geographic I/O  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Raster Data</title>
      <link>/read/geospatial-raster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/geospatial-raster/</guid>
      <description>Reading Geospatial Textbook: Geocomputation with R (Lovelace, Nowosad, Muenchow)
 Chapter 2.2: Raster Data Chapter 3.3: Manipulating raster objects Chapter 4.3: Raster spatial operations  Watch Spatial Analysis in R with sf and raster</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Raster and Vector Data</title>
      <link>/read/geospatial-raster-vector/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/geospatial-raster-vector/</guid>
      <description>Reading Geospatial Textbook: Geocomputation with R (Lovelace, Nowosad, Muenchow)
 Chapter 2.1: Vector Data Chapter 2.2: Raster Data
 Chater 3.2: Vector attribute manipulation
 Chapter 3.3: Manipulating raster objects
 Chapter 4.2: Vector spatial operations
 Chapter 4.3: Raster spatial operations
  Watch Spatial Analysis in R with sf and raster</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Vector Data</title>
      <link>/read/geospatial-vector/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/geospatial-vector/</guid>
      <description>Reading Geospatial Textbook: Geocomputation with R (Lovelace, Nowosad, Muenchow)
 Chapter 2.1: Vector Data Chater 3.2: Vector attribute manipulation Chapter 4.2: Vector spatial operations  Watch Spatial Analysis in R with sf and raster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting help</title>
      <link>/read/getting-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/getting-help/</guid>
      <description> R&amp;rsquo;s Documentation Getting Help Guide 1.6: Getting Help  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Basics &amp; Importing Data</title>
      <link>/read/git-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/git-1/</guid>
      <description> Watch  DataCamp Lesson: RStudio IDE, Part II, Chapter 2: Version Control (by Garrett Grolemund).  Yes, we&amp;rsquo;re starting with Chapter 2 on Version Control, you&amp;rsquo;ll encounter making your own Packages later on.
Read  Git Setup: HappyGitWithR.com Data Import: [r4ds-11]  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grouping and Summarizing</title>
      <link>/read/dplyr-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/dplyr-2/</guid>
      <description> Watch  Tidyverse Chapter 3: Grouping and Summarizing (David Robinson)  Read  group_by, summarize and friends [r4ds-5.6 - 5.7]  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iterate using purrr</title>
      <link>/read/purrr-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/purrr-1/</guid>
      <description>Watch Chapters 3 &amp;amp; 4 of Writing Functions in R. Theste two chapters are focused on purrr and it&amp;rsquo;s use in iteration, particulaly the map() family. It may seem surprising that these tools for iteration are buried in the second half of a course on writing functions, but as you will see, these concepts are closely linked through a style known as functional programming, which is particularly relevant to much data science type analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iteration</title>
      <link>/read/iteration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/iteration/</guid>
      <description>Watch  DataCamp Lesson: Functional Programming: Chapter 3 of Writing Functions in R.  Read  R for Data Science textbook on Iteration: [r4ds-21]  Note that simulations in time we are writing are an example of a sequential process, where each iteration depends on the previous iteration. These cannot be abstracted into apply or map functions. However, iterating over multiple parameters can!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules</title>
      <link>/modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modules/</guid>
      <description>Climate Change   Tabular data What is the evidence for a changing climate? In this unit, we will examine some of the most important indicators of global climate change: including CO2 concentration, global mean temperature, sea level rise, land ice sheet melt, and arctic sea ice cover. We will wrangle a wide range of tabular data file formats used by NOAA and other agencies and introduce the fundamentals of data visualization with ggplot2 and data processing with basic functions from the readr, tidyr, and dplyr packages as we seek to replicate the principle results of climate change over the last decades and also the past thousands of years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Markdown Basics</title>
      <link>/read/rmarkdown-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/rmarkdown-basics/</guid>
      <description>Watch  Reports with RMarkdown (by Garrett Grolemund)  Focus is on chapter 1 and chapter 2, though aside from a few hints most of this is self-explanatory. Feel free to check out chapters 3 and 4 for more information on some of the other output formats and advanced features of RMarkdown. Please note that we will mostly be using the github_document format and not the html_document format.
Read  Introduction [r4ds-27.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REST APIs and web queries</title>
      <link>/read/httr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/httr/</guid>
      <description>Watch Working with Web Data in R</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading for 2017-09-21</title>
      <link>/read/workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/workflows/</guid>
      <description>For Thursday&amp;rsquo;s class, please read the following two short sections:
 6. Workflow: scripts, and 8. Workflow: projects  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading for 2017-10-26</title>
      <link>/read/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/docker/</guid>
      <description>Install Docker (Community Edition, free &amp;amp; open source) for your laptop. (Mac, Windows, &amp;amp; Linux)
 Launch the Docker command line, and run: docker pull rocker/tidyverse to download the image we&amp;rsquo;ll be using in class. This is a large download (689 MB), so please attempt this ahead of time since we won&amp;rsquo;t all be able to download it at once. If either of these steps do not work for you, don&amp;rsquo;t worry, we should be able to fix any special cases in class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relational Data</title>
      <link>/read/dplyr-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/dplyr-3/</guid>
      <description> Watch  DataCamp Lesson: Joining Data with dplyr (Garrett Grolemund)  Yes, this whole lesson is useful to really cover joins. You&amp;rsquo;ll get most of what you need for the module with chapter 1, but take a look at the topics and videos of the later chapters as well.
Read  Relational Data (*_join functions) r4ds-13.1 - 13.7  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup</title>
      <link>/read/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/setup/</guid>
      <description> Watch  DataCamp Lesson: RStudio IDE, Part I (by Garrett Grolemund).  Read  Prerequisites Running R code RStudio Cheat sheet (for reference)
 Style guide Consistent style is an important element of communication and collaboration.
Please review sections 1. Files and 2. Syntax. Most Syntax conventions can be automatically checked with lintr::lint(&amp;quot;assignment.Rmd&amp;quot;).
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strings and regex</title>
      <link>/read/strings-regex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/strings-regex/</guid>
      <description> Watch String Manipulation in R
Reading  Read the opening sections of chapter 13 on Strings and working with Regular Expressions: Sections 14.1 - 14.3.  References </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tools/</guid>
      <description>  GitHub     R    cloud Cloud computing     Docker               </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorials</title>
      <link>/tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;  GitHub
Almost everything we do will involve GitHub in some way. This tutorial will provide a brief introduction to our GitHub-based workflow and review common git patterns for resolving issues you may encounter in working collaboratively.
  RMarkdown Notebooks Most of your work will take place inside an RMarkdown notebook. While we will rely primarily on the github_document format, RMarkdown supports a wide variety of output formats that you can use to create pdf documents (including particular journal formats) slideshows, websites, ebooks and interactive tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization Basics</title>
      <link>/read/ggplot-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/ggplot-1/</guid>
      <description> Watch  Tidyverse Chapter 2: Data Visualization (David Robinson)  (Yes, we&amp;rsquo;re starting with Chapter 2, we&amp;rsquo;ll go back to Chapter 1 soon).
Read  Data Exploration [r4ds-2] First Steps [r4ds-3.2] Aesthetic mappings [r4ds-3.3] Common problems [r4ds-3.4] Facets r4ds-3.5 Geometric objects r4ds-3.6  Reference  Data Visualization Cheat Sheet cheatsheets-ggplot2-2.1  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Websites</title>
      <link>/read/websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/websites/</guid>
      <description>This class will be a tutorial unit on making websites in R. Being familiar with the basic elements of web design (HTML, CSS, domain names) able being able to quickly build a lightweight website is an important skill for any data scientist, although rarely part of data science curriculum. Our goal will be to introduce some of the common platforms and strategies for building a website. Unlike our modules, tutorials are aimed more at exposure than mastery of any particular concepts or tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing R Packages</title>
      <link>/read/r-pkgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/r-pkgs/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s class will introduce the basic idea of an R package as a fundamental unit for sharing re-usable R functions. We will re-organize our population dynamics assignment repo into the structure required for an R package.
While writing a minimal R package is really pretty simple, R packages are still considered an advanced topic and rightly the subject of completely separate books. We recommend Hadley Wickham&amp;rsquo;s Writing R Packages which is available in press or online for more detailed reading.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>